# Naveen Kumar

+91 86703 00541 Bengaluru, Karnataka naveenkumarsangi@pm.me

## Senior Full-Stack Developer

GitHub: nkprince007 LinkedIn: naveenkumarsangi Website: naveenkumarsangi.me

I am a skilled professional with 5 years of experience in the fields of Full-Stack Web and Mobile app development. I am seeking the position in a growth-oriented company where I can use my skills to the advantage of the company with the scope of developing my own skill set.

#### **SKILLS**

**Frameworks** Django, Node.js, React, Angular, Vue, Flutter, Cordova

Languages Python, TypeScript, Dart, Go

Other tools MySQL, Postgres+postgis, TimescaleDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, celery, Rabbitmq

**Communication** English, Hindi, Telugu (native)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Sr. Full-Stack Engineer

July 2018 — Present

Viper Development UG (haftungsbeschränkt)

Hamburg, Germany (Remote)

#### Undisclosed Project A

- Improved API response times by 20 times on report generation pipelines
- · Reduced database clutter with flat hypertables using time-partitioning on TimescaleDB
- Designed a reusable filtering architecture for report generation

#### Undisclosed Project B

- · Developed a real-time IOT focused web application to collect telematics information from automobile suspension kits
- · Extended the real-time data platform to provide historical ride quality information on selected roads

#### Undisclosed Project C

- · Worked on building a web-based desktop application to organize and manage infrared images from CNC tools
- Added support to map critical data points on the image to perform quality checks on materials

#### myndpaar.de

- · Wire-framing and building a cross platform mobile application for couples counseling in association with myndwerk GmbH
- Engaging users to perform various activities using automated push notifications
- Added in-app payments support for monthly subscriptions

Full-Stack Engineer

May 2021 — July 2021

Auguan

Bangalore, India (Part-time)

• Building data pipelines for financial news collection from several search engines

- Redesigned interface for complex graph visualizations between entities
- · Maintaining and deploying data pipelines to kubernetes

#### Full-Stack Engineer / Developer Tools

Dec 2016 — July 2018

GitMate UG

Hamburg, Germany (Remote)

- Helped in building a universal code linter that supports multiple languages using a single config file
- Built a linting pipeline from scratch to manage continuous integration for several customers
- Designed an open-source reusable plugin architecture to link the linting pipeline to several cloud based Git-hosting services
- Worked on a duplicate issue detection plugin to identify closely matching issues on GitHub projects

Software Engineer May 2017 — June 2017
Wipro Business Solutions Bangalore, India (Intern)

- Designed a native Android application to manage ONVIF compliant cameras
- Added Android Auto support to connect with rear parking cameras in automobiles

#### EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science, University of Illinois at Chicago	2019 - 2021
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, National Institute of Technology, Durgapur	2014 - 2018

#### **ACTIVITIES**

7.6.11.1126	
Mozilla Open Source Support Awardee	2018
Mentor, Google Summer of Code	2018
Mentor, Google Code-In	2018, 2017
Student, Google Summer of Code	2017
Open Source Workshops at NITDGP: Research & Presenter	2016 - 2017